Inventory of the Papers of Judge Pierce Lively 1972-1997
University of Virginia, Arthur J. Morris Law Library
- No. 74-2095. Weldon, Dahlari, et al v. Monroe County Probate Court, et al. 1976-1977 (Box 31)
- No. 75-1985. Wells, John, et al v. Murray State University. 1970 (Box 31)
- Nos. 82-1362/1385. Wilson v. Beebe. 1985, 2 folders (Box 31)
- No. 94-2373. Wixson, Georgiana A., et al v. Dowagiac Nursing Home, et al. 1994-1996 (Box 31)
- No. 77-1546. Wright, John v. State of Tennessee. 1980 (Box 31)
- No. 93-3061. Wulf, Russell and Ronald Reutsehler v. Quantum Chemical Corporation, Quantum Employee Stock Ownership Plan for Hourly Represented Employees. 1993-1994 (Box 32)
- No. 93-3488. Yellow Freight System, Inc. v. Robert B. Reich, Secretary of Labor and Willie W. Smith. 1993-1994 (Box 32)
- Sixth Circuit Administrative Files:
- Ad Hoc Court Committees. 1986 (Box 32)
- Advisory Committee on Rules. 1984-1988, 2 folders (Box 32)
- Advisory Committee Meeting. 1986 (Box 32)
- Chambers Assignments. 1985 (Box 32)
- Committees of the United States Court of Appeals. Sixth Circuit. 1983-1984 (Box 32)
- Committee to Recommend Senior Staff Attorney. 1976 (Box 32)
- Docket Control Committee. 1979-1982, 2 folders (Box 32)
- Docket Control Committee. 1984-1988, 3 folders (Box 33)
- Gramm, Rudman, Hollins Legislation. [Reduction of court costs] 1986 (Box 33)
- Library Committee. 1983 (Box 33)
- Motions Practice Subcommittee. 1986 (Box 33)
- Sixth Circuit Court and Council Meetings:
- Court Meeting. [Court practices and procedures] 1983 (Box 34)
- Court Meeting Minutes. 1984-1988, 12 folders (Box 34)
- Circuit Council. Powers, Functions, Duties. 1974 (Box 34)
- Council Meetings. Chief Judge Lively. 1983-1988, 14 folders (Box 35-36)
- Chief Judge - General:
- Circuit Executive. Correspondence. (Illustrative Materials) 1978-1983 (Box 37)
- Change-Over. Judge Lively Stepped Down as Chief Circuit Judge. 1988 (Box 37)
- Clerks= Office. Correspondence. (Illustrative Materials) 1983 (Box 37)
- Conference of Chief Judges. 1983 (Box 37)
- Conference of Chief Judges. Minutes. 1983 (Box 37)
- Conference of Chief Judges. 28 USC 372(c). Judicial Misconduct and Disability. 1984-1986 (Box 37)
- Death Penalty Rule. 1985 (Box 37)
- Division of Duties between Clerk and Circuit Executive. (Illustrative Materials) 1985 (Box 37)
- Interview with Judge Lively. 1986 (Box 37)
- Judge James Ryan. 1986-1987 (Box 37)
- Judges Meeting. Detroit. 1984 (Box 38)
- Louisville Courthouse Construction. 1987
- Miscellaneous Chief Judge Materials. 1983-1986 (Box 38)
- New Procedures. 1983-1991 (Box 38)
- Non Appropriated Funds. 1984 (Box 38)
- Pre-Argument Conference. 1984 (Box 38)
- Reassignment of Cases Following a Death of a Judge. Cases Assigned to Judge Phillips. 1985 (Box 38)
- Testimonies Before Congressional Committees. 1984-1986 (Box 38)
- Testimonies Before the Intercircuit Tribunal. 1984-1985 (Box 39)
- Time-consuming Issues for Chief Judges. Examples. 1987-1988 (Box 39)
- Chief Judge - Bankruptcy:
- Ad Hoc Screening Committee. Bankruptcy Appointments. 1985 (Box 39)
- Bankruptcy Act of 1984. 1984 (Box 39)
- Bankruptcy Appointments. 1984-1985, 2 folders (Box 39)
- Bankruptcy Interim Model. 1984 (Box 39)
- Bankruptcy Interim Model. Kentucky. Western. 1987, 2 folders (Box 39)
- Bankruptcy Interim Model. Ohio. Southern. (The Bankruptcy Amendments of 1984 placed responsibility in the courts of appeals for appointing bankruptcy judges) 1986-1987, 2 folders (Box 40)
- Bankruptcy Judge Procedure - Ad Hoc Committee. 1982-1983 (Box 40)
- Bankruptcy Screening Committees. 1985-1986 (Box 40)
- Bankrupts Legislation. Reform Act of 1978 and Act of 1980. 1977-1983 (Box 40)
- Committee on Bankruptcy Judge Appointments. 1983-1984, 2 folders (Box 40)
- Committee to Review Bankruptcy Judge Positions. 1982 (Box 40)
- Lighter Caseloads. Bankruptcy Judges. 1986 (Box 40)
- Retirement for Bankruptcy Judges. 1987 (Box 40)
- Judicial Conference -- General:
- Committee Survey. 1987 (Box 41)
- Conference of Chief Judges. 1984 (Box 41)
- Conference of Chief Judges. Ad Hoc Committee on Attorney Fees. 1984 (Box 41)
- Conference of Chief Judges. Study Committee. Work of Circuit Councils. 1986 (Box 41)
- Conference Review Committee. 1986-1989 (Box 41)
- Judicial Conference of the United States. 1984-1987 (Box 41)
- Judicial Conference of the United States. Committees. 1987 (Box 41)
- Judicial Conference of the United States. Study Committee. 1986-1987 (Box 41)
- Judicial Conference of the United States. Committee Membership and Jurisdiction. 1988 (Box 41)
- Judicial Conference. Planning Committee. Studies of Other Conferences. 1976-1985 (Box 41)
- Ninth Circuit Judicial Conference. 1983-1985 (Box 42)
- Sixth Circuit Judicial Court of the United States Conferences. 1980-1987, 1989, 1992, 9 folders (Box 42)
- Standing Committee on Rules of Practice and Procedure of the Judicial Conference:
- Standing Committee on Rules of Practice and Procedure. Meetings. 1987-1989, 5 folders (Box 43-44)
- Standing Committee on Rules of Practice and Procedure. General Correspondence. 1987-1989 (Box 44)
- Standing Committee on Rules of Practice and Procedure. Subcommittee on Local Rules. 1988, 3 folders (Box 44)
- Advisory Committee on Federal Rules of Appellate Procedure (FRAP):
- Advisory Committee. 1980 (Box 45)
- Advisory Committee. Correspondence. 1981-1982 (Box 45)
- Advisory Committee. Meeting 12/14/1979 1979 (Box 45)
- Advisory Committee Meeting, 11/15-16/1982. [Judge Lively First Meeting as Chairman of FRAP Committee] 1982, 2 folders (Box 45)
- Advisory Committee Meeting, 12/1983 1983 (Box 45)
- Advisory Committee Meeting, 4/23/1985 1985 (Box 46)
- Advisory Committee Meeting, 12/3/1986. [Judge Lively=s Final Meeting as Chairman of FRAP Committee]. 1980 (Box 46)
- Advisory Committee. Membership. 1982-1986 (Box 46)
- Committee on Rules of Practice and Procedure Standing Committee. 1982-1983 (Box 46)
- Committee Report. Carol Ann Mooney. 1985-1987 (Box 46)
- Committee Report. Ken Ripple. 1986-1987 (Box 46)
- Correspondence. 1985-1990 (Box 46)
- Federal Magistrate Act. Rules Changes Finally Adopted. 1982-1983 (Box 46)
- Judge Lively=s Clerks= Meeting. 1982 (Box 46)
- Rule 30 Report. 1984 (Box 47)
- Rules Adopted, 11/15/1982 with changes in Magistrates Rules as 6/16/1983. 1982-1983 (Box 47)
- Correspondence, Speeches, etc.:
- American Inns of Court Professionalism Award. 1997 (Box 47)
- Antitrust Institute. 1984 (Box 47)
- Archival Note. 1996 (Box 47)
- Congressional Testimony. 1984-1986 (Box 47)
- Correspondence. 1974-1992, 3 folders (Box 47)
- Judge Anthony J. Celebrezze. 1983-1993 (Box 48)
- Detroit Law School. 1986-1987 (Box 48)
- Judge George Edwards. 1986 (Box 48)
- Federal Civil Litigation Seminar. 1996 (Box 48)
- Federal Court Study Committee. 1989-1992 (Box 48)
- Federal Judicial Center. 1973 (Box 48)
- Justice Wendell H. Ford. 1988 (Box 48)
- Chief Judge Boyce F. Martin. 1997 (Box 48)
- Judge Romano Mazzoli 1987-1988 (Box 48)
- Mitch McConnell. 1985-1991 (Box 48)
- Wade H. McCree Memorial. 1987 (Box 48)
- Chief Judge Gilbert S. Merritt. 1988-1989 (Box 48)
- National Seminar for Judges of US Courts of Appeals. 1988 (Box 48)
- David Nelson. 1985 (Box 48)
- Justice Sandra O=Connor. 1985-1991 (Box 48)
- Judge John Peck. 1993 (Box 48)
- Judge Harry Phillips. 1984 (Box 48)
- Portrait Presentation. Ruth Nestor Painter. 1991 (Box 48)
- Justice Lewis Powell. 1988-1989 (Box 48)
- Ken Ripple. 1990 (Box 48)
- Speeches. 1973-1991 (Box 48)
- Justice Potter Stewart. 1994 (Box 49)
- Judge Mac Swinford 1984-1985 (Box 49)
- Miscellany:
- Continuing Judicial Education, Seminars for Federal Judges. Example; Federal Judicial Center Seminar on Constitutional Adjudication and the Judicial Process in the Federal courts. 1986 (Box 49)
- Notes of the US Law Week Supreme Court Reports. n.d., 2 folders (Box 49)
- Notes about the briefs in each case. Examples. 1988-1992 (Box 49)
- Retirement Newspaper Articles. 1997 (Box 50)
- Unpublished Decisions Prior to 1985 that do not appear in WestLaw, with few exceptions. n.d. (Box 50)
- Published Materials:
- Hearing before the Subcommittee on Courts of the Committee on the Judiciary United States Senate, 95th Cong., 1st Sess., S.704 (1985) (Witness Pierce Lively, chief judge, US Court of Appeals for the Sixth Circuit) (Box 50)
- Oversight Hearing before the Subcommittee on Courts, Civil Liberties, and the Administration of Justice of the Committee on the Judiciary House of Representatives, 95th Cong., 1st Sess. (1985) (Pierce Lively, chief judge, Sixth Circuit Court of Appeals Prepared Statement) (Box 50)
- Pierce Lively, A Tribute and Challenge to Exceptional Law Students, 77 Ky L. J. (1988-89) (Box 50)
- Pierce Lively, A View from Below, 4 Det. C. L. Rev. (1986) (Box 50)
- Pierce Lively, Forward, 15 U. Tol. L. Rev., (1984) (Box 50)
- Practitioners= Handbook for Appeals to the United States Court of Appeals for the Sixth Circuit. Prepared by the Cincinnati Chapter of the Federal Bar Association, 4 ed., May 1984. (Box 50)
- Report of the Proceedings of the Judicial Conference of the United States. March 17, 1987. Washington, D. C., 1987. (Box 50)
- Sixth Circuit Federal Practice Manual. (Prepared by the Cincinnati Chapter-Federal Bar Association. Cincinnati, Anderson Publishing Co., 1993. (Box 50)
- 2 Large Card Files of Cases, organized in alphabetical order. (Box 50)
- Card Files organized by subject., 1 box (Box 51)